玛德琳？
Madeleine?
你还想吃东西吗？
You want to eat again?
你吃得太多是因为你情绪低落
You eat too much because you're depressed.
玛德琳！
Madeleine!
什么事？
Yes?
玛德琳！
Madeleine!
什么事 妈妈？
Yes, mama?
我渴了 我的天使
I'm thirsty, my angel.
我来了
I'm coming.
- 你要吃药吗？- 是的 亲爱的
- Do you want your medicine? - Yes, my darling.
你想玩游戏吗？
Do you want to play a game?
我在等爸爸回家
I'm waiting for Papa to come home.
你认为爸爸是做什么的？
What do you think Papa does?
他是一个医生
He's a doctor.
他医治人
He heals people.
哦不 不
Oh. No, no.
你爸爸 他杀人
Your Papa, he kills people.
- 没有 - 这就是你爱的人吗？杀人犯吗？
- No. - Is that who you love? Murderers?
- 妈妈 - 妈妈妈妈妈妈！
- Mama. - Mama. Mama. Mama!
离开我去玩
Leave me be. Go play.
妈妈！
Mama!
别管我！
Leave me alone!
妈妈！
Mama!
- 怀特先生在家吗？- 没有 他走了
- Is Mr. White home? - No. He's gone.
我叫吕瑟弗·萨芬
My name is Lyutsifer Safin.
你丈夫杀了我的家人
Your husband killed my family.
我告诉过你 他走了
I told you, he's gone.
- 我知道 - 这会让他更痛苦
- I know. - This will hurt him more.
你没事吧？
You okay?
是的
Yes.
我们走吧
Let's go.
是如何看待？
How's the view?
我越来越喜欢它了
It's growing on me.
你能开快点吗？
Can you go faster?
我们不需要走得更快
We don't need to go faster.
我们有的是时间
We have all the time in the world.
你忍不住要回头看
You can't help looking over your shoulder.
- 什么？- 没人会来
- What? - No one is coming.
我没有小心翼翼
I wasn't looking over my shoulder.
- 不 你是 - 没有
- Yes, you were. - No.
我们要为这事吵架吗？
Are we gonna have a row about this?
他们在烧什么？
What are they burning?
的秘密的愿望放下过去
Secrets. Wishes. Letting go of the past.
扔掉旧东西 迎接新事物
Getting rid of old things, in come the new.
你去了哪里？
Where did you go to?
今天 在河边嗯？
Today, by the water. Hmm?
告诉我
Tell me.
如果你告诉我维斯帕的事 我就告诉你
I'll tell you if you tell me about Vesper.
这就是我们来这里的原因吗？
Is that why we're here?
她被葬在雅典卫城
She's buried at the acropolis.
我知道她被埋在哪里了
I know where she's buried.
你能原谅她吗？为我们吗？
Can you forgive her? For us?
我很久以前就离开她了
I left her behind a long time ago.
只要我们回头看 过去就没死
As long as we're looking over our shoulder, the past is not dead.
你必须让她走 即使很难
You have to let her go, even if it's hard.
你是说 如果我们有未来的话？
You mean, um, if we're to have a future?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
所以 我这样做了 然后我会告诉你我所有的秘密
So, I do this, and then… I'll tell you all my secrets.
好吧
Okay.
我要去做这个 然后回来吃早饭
I'm going to go and do this, and then I'm going to come back for breakfast.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
然后你要告诉我我们接下来要去哪里
And then you're going to tell me where we're going next.
回家
Home.
我想念你的
I miss you.
什么…
What…
玛德琳？
Madeleine?
布洛菲尔德向您问好
Blofeld sends his regards.
你知道的…玛德琳 她是幽灵党的女儿
You know… Madeleine, she is a daughter of Spectre.
她是幽灵党的女儿
She's a daughter of Spectre.
你的行李已经下来了 邦德先生
Your baggage is already down, Mr. Bond.
按你妻子的要求
As your wife requested.
你是对的
You were right.
放手很难
Letting go is hard.
詹姆斯
James.
发生了什么事？
What happened?
- 发生了什么事？- 他们怎么知道我在这里？
- What happened? - How did they know I was here?
- 你在说什么？- 玛德琳 他们怎么知道我在这里？
- What are you talking about? - Madeleine, how did they know I was here?
- 我不知道你是… - 幽灵党 他们是怎么知道的？
- I have no idea what you're… - Spectre. How did they know?
你在说什么？詹姆斯！
What are you talking about? James!
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
我们离开
We're leaving.
我有件事要告诉你
There is something I need to tell you.
我打赌有
I bet there is.
詹姆斯！
James!
把它捡起来把它捡起来！
Pick it up. Pick it up!
是布洛菲尔德 亲爱的
It's Blofeld, my love.
你父亲会为你感到骄傲的
Your father would be so proud of you.
你的牺牲将是我们的荣耀
Your sacrifice will be our glory.
- 我不明白 - 布拉沃
- I don't understand. - Bravo.
- 你好 - 放羊出去 孩子
- Hello. - Let the sheep out, kid.
- 为什么？- 不然我就杀了你
- Why? - Because otherwise I'll kill you.
詹姆斯，为什么？我为什么要背叛你？
James, why? Why would I betray you?
我们都有自己的秘密 只是你的还没有
We all have our secrets, we just didn't get to yours yet.
詹姆斯詹姆斯 听我说
James. James, listen to me.
我宁愿死也不愿你认为我…
I'd rather die than you think I'm…
詹姆斯！
James!
做点什么詹姆斯！
Do something. James!
说点什么，詹姆斯！
Say something, James!
请
Please.
好吧
Okay.
来吧
Come on.
就这样了？
So, this is it?
这是它
This is it.
我怎么知道你没事？
How will I know that you're okay?
你不会
You won't.
你再也见不到我了
You'll never see me again.
《007系列之无暇赴死》
∮ 我应该知道的 ∮
∮ I should have known. ∮
∮ 我会一个人离开 ∮
∮ I'd leave alone. ∮
∮ 让我们看看 ∮
∮ Just goes to show. ∮
∮ 你流的血 ∮
∮ That the blood you bleed. ∮
∮ 只是你欠的血 ∮
∮ Is just the blood you owe. ∮
∮ 我们曾经是一对 ∮
∮ We were a pair. ∮
∮ 但是我看到你在那里 ∮
∮ But I saw you there. ∮
∮ 无法承受 ∮
∮ Too much to bear. ∮
∮ 你就是我的生命 ∮
∮ You were my life. ∮
∮ 但是生活离公平很远 ∮
∮ But life is far away From fair. ∮
∮ 我爱你是不是太傻了？∮
∮ Was I stupid to love you? ∮
∮ 我是鲁莽的吗？∮
∮ Was I reckless to help? ∮
∮ 其他人都明白吗？∮
∮ Was it obvious to everybody else? ∮
∮ 我爱上了一个谎言♬ ∮
∮ That I'd fallen for a lie. ∮
∮ 你从来不站在我这一边 ∮
∮ You were never on my side. ∮
∮ 骗我一次 骗我两次 ∮
∮ Fool me once, fool me twice. ∮
∮ 你是死亡还是天堂？∮
∮ Are you death or paradise? ∮
∮ 现在你再也不会看到我哭泣 ∮
∮ Now you'll never See me cry. ∮
∮ 没有时间去死 ∮
∮ There's just no time to die. ∮
∮ 我让它燃烧 ∮
∮ I let it burn. ∮
∮ 你不再是我的牵挂 ∮
∮ You're no longer my concern. ∮
∮ 过去的脸回来了 ∮
∮ Faces from my past return. ∮
∮ 另一个有待学习的教训 ∮
∮ Another lesson yet to learn. ∮
∮ 我爱上了一个谎言♬ ∮
∮ That I'd fallen for a lie. ∮
∮ 你从来不站在我这一边 ∮
∮ You were never on my side. ∮
∮ 骗我一次 骗我两次 ∮
∮ Fool me once, fool me twice. ∮
∮ 你是死亡还是天堂？∮
∮ Are you death or paradise? ∮
∮ 现在你再也不会看到我哭泣 ∮
∮ Now you'll never See me cry. ∮
∮ 没有时间去死 ∮
∮ There's just no time to die. ∮
∮ 没时间死 ∮
∮ No time to die. ∮
我们在
We're in.
继续
Proceed.
由于服务器的维护计划 请记住在今晚10点前备份所有数据
Please remember to back up all data by 10:00 p.m. this evening due to planned server maintenance.
你没事吧？
You okay?
你知道SL5吗 我今早用的武器化天花？
You know the, uh, SL5, the weaponized smallpox I was using this morning?
你看到了吗？…我把它放在那该死的…瓦尔多 你没见过天花吧？
Have you seen it? I… I put it in the bloody… Valdo, you haven't seen a tub of smallpox, have you?
这汤不错
This was a good soup.
现在它是浪费 即使它是一个笑话
Now it is waste, even if it is joke.
我的西红柿汤里的东西比你们两个脑子里的东西加起来还要复杂
There is more complexity in my tomato soup than in both of your brains combined.
瓦尔多 你太刻薄了真是…总有一天我会把埃博拉病毒放进你的茶里
Valdo, that is so unkind. It's so… One day I will put Ebola in your tea.
然后我会看着你们脸上的血汗… …我会笑的
And then I will watch as your faces sweat blood… …and I will be laughing.
- 好保持冷静 - 哇
- Nice. Keep your hair on. - Wow.
他的想象力真丰富 不是吗？
He's got a terrifying imagination, hasn't he?
奥布鲁切夫博士
Dr. Obruchev.
他们来了
They are coming.
- 谁？- 幽灵党
- Who? - Spectre.
- 萨芬 - 不要试图阻止他们
- Safin. - Do not try to stop them.
这就是我们一直在等待的
This is what we've been waiting for.
他们会让你进入四级生物安全冰箱取出武器
They will ask you to enter Bio Security Level Four fridge and remove the weapon.
不能让任何人看到你在做什么
No one must see what you are doing.
他们不会杀你的他们认为他们需要你
They will not kill you. They think they need you.
他们不会杀我吧？
They will not kill me?
正在传输文件
Transferring the files as we speak.
现在完成了我该拿它做什么？
Now… Now it's done. What do I do with it?
往下咽再见
Swallow it. Goodbye.
咽下…是的 我喜欢动物！
Swallow the… Yes, I like animals!
再见
Bye-bye.
危险 发现非法访问
Danger, illegal access detected.
立即保护所有生物有害物质
Secure all biohazardous materials immediately.
动！遵循！
Move! Follow!
- 不！不！- 谨慎
- No! No! - Caution.
在这个区域有未经授权的人员
Unauthorized personnel located in this sector.
拜托 我们是科学家 我们没有武器
Please, we're scientists, we're unarmed.
我们手无寸铁的你想要什么？
We're unarmed. What do you want?
瓦尔多·奥布鲁切夫
Valdo Obruchev.
你好
Hello.
打开生物安全四级冰箱
Open the Bio Security Level Four fridge.
- 嗯… - 把武器给我
- And, uh… - Give me the weapon.
武器…什么武器？我们有…赫拉克勒斯
The weap… What weapon? We have, uh… Heracles.
它需要双重身份验证
It requires double authentication.
哪一个？
Which one?
他
Him.
哈代哈代！不要让他们
Hardy. Hardy! Don't let them.
不要让他们请不要让他们得逞
Don't let them. Don't let them, please.
哦
Oh.
警告 设施正在封锁
Warning, facility lockdown in progress.
所有出口都已封锁
All exits are now sealed.
警告 设施正在封锁
Warning, facility lockdown in progress.
所有出口都已封锁
All exits are now sealed.
哦 这是…是安全带吗？这个？
Oh, what is, uh… It's a safety belt? This?
哇
Wow.
我不能！
I… I cannot!
这里没有电梯！
There is no elevator!
磁体
Magnets.
长官 我刚收到了我见过的最不寻常的东西
Sir, I've just received the most unusual… I've seen it.
哦 耶稣基督
Oh, Jesus Christ.
长官 什么是海格力斯计划？
Sir, what's the Heracles project?
这个实验室不在规定范围内
This lab isn't on the books.
不 它不是
No, it's not.
- 有伤亡 - 是煤气泄漏
- There were casualties. - It was a gas leak.
要我通知首相吗？
Shall I alert the PM?
这是煤气泄漏我将处理它
It was a gas leak. I'll handle it.
斤计较
Moneypenny.
007年在哪里？
Where's 007?
这不是一个惊喜吗 费里斯？
Well, isn't this a surprise, Felix?
詹姆斯
James.
那个金发女郎是谁？
Who's the blond?
洛根·阿什 国务院的很高兴见到你
Logan Ash, State Department. It's really nice to meet you.
久仰大名我是说 我是你的超级粉丝
I've heard a lot about you. I mean, I'm a huge fan.
- 巴比伦 - 警察的男孩
- Babylon. - Police boy.
我需要你帮个忙 兄弟
I need a favor, brother.
你没看到备忘录吗？我退休了
You didn't get the memo? I'm retired.
如果你还在女王手下 我也不会问的
I wouldn't ask if you were still in Her Majesty's Service.
这意味着什么呢？
And what does that mean?
我们的民选领导人在沙箱里表现得不太好
Our elected leaders aren't playing nice in the sandbox.
詹姆斯
James.
有安静的地方我们可以私下谈谈吗？
Is there somewhere quiet where we can talk in private?
安静？是的
Quiet? Yeah.
我希望你能来取个包裹
I was hoping you could pick up a package.
- 5 - 4
- Five. - Four.
包在哪里？
Where's the package?
短途旅行古巴
Short trip. Cuba.
你喜欢那里
You love it there.
哦 我喜欢那里？
Oh, I love it there?
嘿 瓦尔多·奥布鲁切夫
Hey. Valdo Obruchev.
你会说你从没听说过他
You're gonna say you never heard of him.
- 没听说过二 - 三
- Never heard of him. Two. - Three.
啊… 这是一种美好的生活
Ah… It's a good life.
你没听说过他？
You never heard of him?
你在军情六处任职期间 他不是叛变了吗？
Didn't he defect during your tenure at MI6?
奥布鲁切夫三天前在伦敦军情六处的一个秘密实验室被绑架
Obruchev was kiDNApped three days ago from a secret MI6 lab in London.
两天前 他的脸在圣地亚哥德古巴的一次面部识别扫描中被定位了
Two days ago, his mug pinged on a facial recognition sweep in Santiago de Cuba.
他漏掉了最精彩的部分
He's leaving out the best part.
幽灵党
Spectre.
我在那里有个线人 说他们在集合
I have a contact there, says they're gathering.
巧合吗？
Coincidence?
来吧就像以前一样
Come on. It'll be like old times.
- 三个 - 两个
- Three. - Two.
你真的是最适合这份工作的人
You're really the only guy for the job.
- 就是你 - 我请客
- You're the guy. - It's my round.
嗨
Hi.
- 苏格兰威士忌 - 是的 男人
- Scotch. - Yeah, man.
你在哪里找到《摩门经》的？
Where'd you find the Book of Mormon?
- 政治任命 - 不是我的选择
- Political appointee. - Not my choice.
看来智力不再是中心了
Seems intelligence isn't central anymore.
他笑得太多了
He smiles too much.
帮我们把它送到正确的人手里
Help us get this into the right hands.
怎么 你是我的得力助手吗？
Oh, what, and you're the right hands?
我不仅长得漂亮
I'm not just a pretty face.
我很久以前就不相信美女了 费利克斯
I stopped trusting pretty faces a long time ago, Felix.
是的 我听说过坏运气
Yeah, I heard. Bad luck.
- 糟糕的判断 - 是的
- Bad judgment. - Yeah.
现在很难区分好人和坏人 坏人和英雄
Harder to tell the good from bad, villains from heroes these days.
我需要你 詹姆斯
I need you, James.
你是我唯一信任的人
You're the only one I trust with this.
我不是在胡闹
I'm not screwing around.
我想回到我家人身边 告诉他们我又拯救了世界
I wanna get back to my family, tell them I saved the world again.
你不？
Don't you?
很高兴再次见到你 菲利克斯
Nice to see you again, Felix.
- 至少记下我的号码 - 我有你的电话
- At least take my number. - I've got your number.
有麻烦吗？
In trouble?
不断
Constantly.
需要搭车吗？
Need a ride?
确定为什么不呢？
Sure. Why not?
等一等
Hold on.
- 你叫什么名字？- 无关
- What's your name? - Nomi.
- 你的吗？- 詹姆斯叫我詹姆斯
- Yours? - James. Call me James.
- 你是做什么的 诺米？- 我是潜水员
- What do you do, Nomi? - I'm a diver.
- 你潜水干什么？- 我对旧残骸情有独钟
- What do you dive for? - I have a thing for old wrecks.
那你来对地方了
Well, then you've come to the right place.
在你之后
After you.
嗯… 漂亮的房子
Hmm… Nice house.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
那是卧室吗？
Is that the bedroom?
是的 它是
Yes, it is.
这不是我第一次想到你会脱掉的东西 但是…是的
Well, that's not the first thing I thought you'd take off, but, uh… Yeah.
- 邦德先生 你看起来像是一个想要行动的人 - 我们能开门见山吗？
- You seem like a man who's gagging for some action, Mr. Bond. - Shall we cut to the chase?
我是出于职业礼貌来的
I'm here as a professional courtesy.
你可真没礼貌 是吧？
Well, you're not very courteous, are you?
你弄坏了我的车…是邦德指挥官 但你知道的
You've broken my car… It's Commander Bond, but you know that.
- 双零 - 两年
- Double 0? - Two years.
- 非常年轻 - 积极向上
- Very young. - High achiever.
- 哦 上帝啊 - 自从你退休后 世界已经改变了 邦德指挥官
- Oh, Jesus Christ. - The world's moved on since you retired, Commander Bond.
- 也许你没有注意到 - 不 我没有
- Perhaps you didn't notice. - No, can't say I had.
在我看来 这个世界并没有太大的改变
And in my humble opinion, the world doesn't change very much.
你会这么说
You would say that.
听着 这一切看起来就像天堂 这个小泡泡 或者别的什么
Look, this all seems like heaven, this little bubble, or whatever.
但很明显你是一个只有时间可以消磨的人 没有活下去的理由
But it's so obvious you're a man who only has time to kill, nothing to live for.
瓦尔多·奥布鲁切夫是禁区
So Valdo Obruchev is off-limits.
你要是挡我的路 我就一枪崩了你的膝盖
You get in my way, I will put a bullet in your knee.
那个管用的
The one that works.
你得再问自己几个问题
You need to ask yourself a few more questions.
- 军情六处 中情局都在追同一个人 彼此不联系… - 那可不好
- MI6, CIA chasing after the same man, not communicating with each other, that… - That's not good.
你知道吗？代我向M问好 但我不再为他工作了
You know what? Tell M hello, but… I don't work for him anymore.
告诉他自己
Tell him yourself.
顺便说一句 我可不是普通的双0
By the way, I'm not just any old double 0.
我是007年
I'm 007.
你可能以为他们会让它退休
You probably thought they'd retire it.
它只是一个数字
It's just a number.
是的
Yeah.
古巴见？
See you in Cuba?
怎么样了 Q？
How's it going, Q?
奥布鲁切夫的硬盘上有几份大文件被删除了
Several large files seem to have been wiped from Obruchev's hard drive.
- 他在研究一些非常先进的算法… - 你能取回文件吗？- 努力
- He was working on some pretty advanced algorithm… - Can you retrieve the files? - Trying.
把能找到的都给我 然后毁掉硬盘
Get me everything you can and then destroy the drive.
如果我知道更多关于这是什么 我就能…谢谢你 Q
If I knew more about what this was, I could… Thank you, Q. That's all.
是的一分钟总理又打来电话了
Yes. One minute. The PM is calling again.
007 告诉他们一些事情 任何事
007. Tell them something. Anything.
- 007 - M 亲爱的
- 007. - M, darling.
一些东西
Couple of things.
- 邦德 - 我见过你的新007
- Bond. - I met your new 007.
她是个让人放下戒心的年轻女人
She's a disarming young woman.
所以 奥布鲁切夫
So, Obruchev.
你一直雇佣他 对吧？
You kept him on the payroll, didn't you?
别插手这跟你一点关系都没有
Stay out of it. This has nothing to do with you.
是的是幽灵党
It does. It's Spectre.
马洛里 你做了什么？
Mallory, what have you done?
- 00麻烦？- CIA占了优势
- Double 0 trouble? - The CIA have the advantage.
布罗菲尔德
Get me Blofeld.
先生 他只跟他的心理医生说话
Sir, he only speaks to his psychiatrist.
我知道我要的是直播
I know. The live feed's what I want.
它们在中间保持直线
They stay straight in the middle.
然后他们把他带了上来
And then they bring him up.
他每天都这样 像一袋蜜蜂一样疯狂
He's like this every day, mad as a bag of bees.
- 今天是加冕的日子 - 好
- It's crowning day. - Good.
- 什么事？- 这是什么
- What is it? - It's nothing.
- 干净得不能再干净了 - 每个人都想要一个派对
- It's clean as can be. - Everyone just wants a party.
我想让他们俩都听到
Yeah, I want them both to hear me.
是一个惊喜
Be a surprise.
费利克斯，我在
Felix, I'm in.
他在
He's in.
我想让你见见圣地亚哥的一位年轻女士
There's a young lady in Santiago I want you to meet.
帕洛玛？
Paloma?
- 你迟到了走吧 - 我…呃 关于帽子的事？巴黎，嗯…嗯？什么帽子？
- You're late. Vamos. - I… Uh, something about a hat? Paris, uh… Huh? What hat?
我一紧张就会忘事
I forget things when I get nervous.
这是我做过的最大的工作
This is the biggest job I've ever had.
你的房间吗？
This your room?
这是一个酒窖
It's a wine cellar.
好了 到这里来
Okay, come here.
你不觉得我们应该稍微了解一下对方 然后再…哦…不 不 不
Don't you think we ought to get to know each other just a little bit before we, um… Oh… No, no, no.
- 不 抱歉 - 嗯… - 好的 - 你来吧
- Um, no, I'm sorry. - Um… - All right. - You do it.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你介意…
Do you mind, uh…
- 这一定会很棒的 - 我知道
- This is gonna go brilliantly. - I know.
我已经接受了三个星期的训练
I've done three weeks' training.
我们去喝一杯吧
Let's get a drink.
好主意
Good idea.
两杯伏特加马提尼 摇匀 不要搅
Two vodka martinis, shaken, not stirred.
是的 先生
Si, senor.
这样我才能听到你说话
So I can hear you.
我们喝什么？
What shall we drink to?
- 费利克斯？- 费利克斯
- Felix? - To Felix.
提醒我给他买根雪茄
Remind me to get him a cigar.
我们吗？
Vamos?
- 确定 - 好的
- Sure. - Okay.
这个样品您用够了吗？
Will this sample be enough for you?
如果他用过 是的
If he has used it, yes.
它现在正在进步
It is now progressing.
哦对不起
Oops. Sorry.
可怕，可怕的手套那么滑
Terrible, terrible gloves. So slippery.
原谅我
Forgive me.
多久？
How much longer?
啊哈
A-ha.
祝幽灵党有个美好的未来
To happy new future for Spectre.
现在 它准备好了
Now, it is ready.
你去那边
You go that way.
我走这边
I'll go this way.
- 这是什么？- 幽灵党？
- What is this? - Spectre bunga-bunga?
你参加过这样的派对吗？
You ever been to a party like this?
你以为我是怎么得到这份工作的？
How do you think I got this job?
现在 不要分心
Don't get distracted, now.
记住 我们在找那个俄国科学家
Remember, we're looking for our Russian scientist.
我见过很多幽灵党特工
I'm seeing a lot of Spectre agents.
是的
Yes.
看起来他们都是
And it looks like all of them.
哇
Wow.
你的朋友吗？
Friend of yours?
独眼巨人我们在意大利偶遇
Cyclops. We ran into each other in Italy.
那是一次大开眼界的经历
That was an eye-opening experience.
他们戴着耳机
They're wearing earpieces.
扫描
Scanning.
- 会干净的很好 - 再好不过了
- It'll be clean. It's good. - It's as good as can be.
- 这是我的派对 - 啊 找到了
- It's my party. - Ah. Found it.
庆祝我 我的生日 我的加冕日
Celebrate me, my birthday, my crowning day.
生日男孩是谁？
Who's the birthday boy?
- 嗯… - 恩斯特·斯塔夫罗·布洛菲尔德 - 他在吗？
- Um… - Ernst Stavro Blofeld. - Is he here?
- 不 他是… - 走你的路 - 跟着音乐
- No, he's… - Make your way. - Follow the music.
他在伦敦的监狱里
He's in London in prison.
你怎么能确定？
How do you know for sure?
因为是我把他放在那里的
Because I put him there.
感受我温暖的拥抱
…feel my warm embrace.
体验美味的惊喜
Experience a delicious surprise.
让我们用我们的新力量来引导人类
Let us shepherd humanity with our new power.
我发现他了 我们的俄国科学家
I've spotted him, our little Russian scientist.
- 你抓住他了吗？- 我在这里
- Have you got him? - I'm here.
- 我抓住他了 - 陪着他
- I got him. - Stay with him.
但我从我的小眼睛看到了你 我的小眼睛向你问好
But I see you from my little eye, and my little eye says hi.
现在 看 现在 我们就像奥林匹斯山上的神一样从阴影中出现
Now, see, now, we emerge from the shadows as gods on Mount Olympus.
为我们这个贱民的终结干杯
Here's to the end of our pariah.
哦 我的负担 我的兄弟…
Oh, my burden, my brother…
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
再见，詹姆斯
Goodbye, James.
今晚你是受欢迎的
You're popular tonight.
你不能跑
You can't run.
那太迟了
It's too late.
它已经在你的皮肤下爬了
It's already crawling under your skin.
别惊慌 这对我们无害
Don't be alarmed, it's harmless to us.
只是为了他如此美味
Just to him. So delicious.
先生！
Sir!
它是有效的
It is working.
它是有效的只有幽灵党会死
It is working. Only Spectre are dying.
你好
Hello.
- 你是我的esco… - 嗯？- 不是吗？哦
- Are you for my, uh, esco… - Hmm? - No? Oh.
走吧！
Go!
- 谢谢我要这个 - 不！
- Thank you. I'll take this. - No!
- 那是什么？- 让他！
- What was that? - Get him!
时间去我们走吧！
Time to go. Let's go!
很明显
It's clear.
我可以插句话吗？
May I cut in?
- 去找他 - 我来拖住他们
- Go get him. - I'll hold them off.
覆盖出口！
Cover the exits!
帕洛玛
Paloma.
别让他们跑了！
Don't let them get away!
你拿到了吗？
Have you got them?
近
Nearly.
不！
No!
下来！
Down!
- 让他们！- 别让他们跑了！
- Get them! - Don't let them get away!
帕洛玛 我知道你很忙 但这案子就要落幕了
Paloma, I know you're busy, but the curtain's about to come down on this one.
- 我可以买辆车 - 你要放在哪里？
- I can get a car. - Where do you need it?
我马上就来
I'll be right there.
住下来！
Stay down!
动！
Move!
嗯？
Huh?
来吧！
Come on!
三周的训练 真的吗？
Three weeks' training, really?
或多或少
More or less.
我们还是需要那辆车
We're still gonna need that car.
- 祝您健康！- 祝您健康！
- Salud! - Salud!
你要带我去哪里？
Where are you taking me?
我要把你带回妈妈身边 亲爱的
I'm taking you back to Mother, darling.
妈妈吗？哦 不 不 不
Mother? Oh, no, no, no.
嗯你就在那里
Huh. There you are.
不！
No!
呆在那儿！
Stay there!
- 你明白吗？- 我很好
- You okay? - I'm great.
我要借用你的飞机对不起
I'm gonna borrow your plane. Sorry.
这是一个捷径
It's a shortcut.
我到站了再见
This is my stop. Goodbye.
- 你太棒了 - 你太
- You were excellent. - You too.
- 下次多待一会儿 - 我会的
- Next time, stay longer. - I will.
- 给菲利克斯来支雪茄 - 谢谢来吧
- Hey, a cigar for Felix. - Thank you. Come on.
- 再见 - 再见
- Ciao. - Ciao.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
不 不 不 先生 我不想谈这个
No, no, no, sir, I am not getting on that.
真可惜 我们没得选
Well, that's a shame because we don't have a choice.
我们走吧来吧
Let's go. Come on.
好了 好了 这是什么？
Okay, okay, what have we got here?
先生 我刚救了你的命？请记住这一点
Sir, I just saved your life, okay? Please remember that.
所以 你能告诉我这到底是怎么回事吗？
So, could you please tell me what the hell is going on?
你要带我去哪里？
Where are you taking me?
某个地方的安全
Somewhere safe.
至少让它看起来很难
At least make it look hard.
谢了 费里斯 你让我掉进了陷阱进去
Thanks, Felix, you walked me into a trap. Get in.
- 什么陷阱？- 幽灵党死了坐下
- What trap? - Spectre's dead. Sit.
- 谁死了？- 所有人
- Who's dead? - All of them.
好
Good.
这是什么？给我解释一下
What is this? Explain it to me.
我不知道该怎么形容你这样的人
I don't have the words to describe to someone like you.
一个尝试
Try one.
它是完美的
It's perfect.
一个完美的什么？
A perfect what?
什么？刺客
What? Assassin.
谢谢你 邦德 你的任务完成了
Thank you, Bond, your mission's done.
- 为什么我没死？- 你不需要回答那些问题 邦德！- 为什么是幽灵党？
- Why didn't it kill me? - You don't have to answer those questions. Bond! - Why Spectre?
- 邦德 别问这些问题了 - 安静！
- Bond, please stop asking these questions. - Quiet!
说出来
Speak up.
因为你从来都不是目标
Because you were never the intended target.
他是目标？为什么？
He was a target? Why?
按照我们的决定 我改变了DNA
I changed the DNA like we decided.
- 现在这个计划已经完成了 - 我很困惑 - 哇 哇 哇
- Now the plan is complete - And I'm confused. - Whoa, whoa, whoa.
“我们”是谁？是M让你做的吗？
Who is "we"? Did M make you build this?
他太过分了 费里斯
He is out of line here, Felix.
是M命令你杀了幽灵党吗？
Did M order you to kill Spectre?
- 别回答！- M是幕后黑手吗？
- Don't answer that! - Is M behind this?
- 他太过分了！- 菲利克斯！
- He is out of line! - Felix!
阿什 闭上你的嘴！
Ash, shut your mouth!
- M - M帮我建的
- M. - M helped me build it.
- 但是 拜托 他没有远见 - 如何使用它 - 谁知道呢？谁做？
- But please, he does not have the vision - For how to use it. - Well, who does? Who does?
布罗菲尔德吗？他怎么知道我要去那里？
Blofeld? How did he know I was going to be there?
哦！
Oh!
我和萨芬你明白吗？
I'm with Safin. You understand?
是的我是奥布鲁切夫医生
Yes. I am Dr. Obruchev.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我不知道你怎么想 但我直觉告诉我阿什可能不会站在我们这边
I don't know about you, but I got a feeling in my gut Ash might not be on our side.
我们得谈谈你的朋友
We need to have a conversation about the company you keep.
我和你一起
I'm with you.
那可是很多血啊
That's a lot of blood.
那么 我们要去哪里？
So, where are we going?
上飞机 医生
Get in the plane, Doctor.
这可能是我最后一次任务了
This might be my last mission.
- 你觉得呢？- 我觉得你只是在找借口不帮我
- What do you think? - I think you're just looking for an excuse not to help me.
那就这样吧
There you go.
帕洛玛 她给了我一支雪茄让你抽 你就抽吧
Paloma, she gave me a cigar for you to smoke, and you are gonna smoke it.
很好 但也许你现在应该先留着
Nice, but maybe you should hold on to that for now.
你待着别动按住它
You just stay put. Keep the pressure on that.
我会想办法出去的
I'm gonna find us a way out.
我就在这里
I'll be over here.
费里斯 我们真的不能再见面了…
You know, Felix, we really need to stop meeting…
- 哦 - 好的
- Ooh. - Okay.
我是他的超级粉丝
I was such a big fan of his.
费利克斯！
Felix!
这看起来不太好
This doesn't look good.
别这样 费里斯 比这更糟的我们都经历过我们走吧
Come on, Felix, we've been in worse than this. Let's go.
就像我小时候在捕虾船上一样
It's like back when I was a kid on that shrimp boat.
你来自密尔沃基
You're from Milwaukee.
我是吗？我以为那是我编的
Am I? I thought I made that up.
他有我
He got me.
让我走吧让我走
Just let me go. Let me go.
你有这个吗？
You got this?
是的是的
Yeah. Yeah.
让它值得
Make it worth it.
詹姆斯 这是美好的生活 不是吗？
James, it's a good life, isn't it?
最好的
The best.
费利克斯
Felix.
费利克斯费利克斯
Felix. Felix.
- 名字吗？- 邦德
- Name? - Bond.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
退休怎么样？
How's retirement?
安静
Quiet.
嗨 奥布鲁切夫在哪？
Hi. Where's Obruchev?
我以为你们俩会合得来
I thought you two would get along.
- 报告 007 - 谢谢
- Report, 007. - Thank you.
00…7
00…7.
那一定让你很烦恼
That must bother you.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
他为了别人离开了我
He left me for somebody else.
- 这是 呃… - 所以你跟丢了？- 你可以进去了
- It's, uh… - So, you lost him? - You can go in.
- 谢谢 - …独自一人，我害怕
- Thank you. - Thank y… Alone, I'm afraid.
哦 这让你烦恼吗？
Oh, does that bother you?
我知道你为什么开枪打他
I get why you shot him.
是啊 每个人都至少试过一次
Yeah, well, everyone tries at least once.
这张桌子变大了吗？
Has this desk got bigger?
或者你有小号的吗？
Or have you got smaller?
邦德 你离开我们的时候 我不能假装没有人对你表示遗憾
I can't pretend there weren't some sorry faces when you left us, Bond.
但你消失得太远了 我们以为你肯定死了
But you fell so far off the grid that we thought you must be dead.
现在 得知你实际上还活着 而且还在为中央情报局工作 嗯…
Now, learning that you were, in fact, alive and well, and… working for the CIA, well…
好吧 那确实是个打击
Well, that really was a blow.
他们很友好地问我
Well, they just asked so nicely.
真遗憾 你还没有失去你的能力
It's a shame that you haven't lost your touch.
我们就不会陷入这种困境
We wouldn't be in this mess.
这是你的烂摊子
This is your mess.
布洛菲尔德在古巴想杀我 但有人劫持了他的计划
Blofeld tried to kill me in Cuba, but someone hijacked his plan.
而偷了你武器的人却用它消灭了幽灵党
And whoever stole your weapon used it to wipe out Spectre instead.
现在你的武器在逃 似乎没人知道它在谁手里
Now your weapon is on the run and nobody seems to know who has it.
所以你可以想象我为什么回来打球
So you can imagine why I've come back to play.
我们正在调查
We're looking into it.
我能认出绑架奥布鲁切夫的人
I can identify the man that took Obruchev.
你想要什么回报 邦德？
And what do you want in return, Bond?
布罗菲尔德
Blofeld.
不可能的他在贝尔马什
Impossible. He's in Belmarsh.
是的他在古巴贝尔马什主持了一次幽灵党会议
Yes. He ran a Spectre meeting in Cuba from Belmarsh.
- 如何？- 没有
- How? - No.
如何？没人有权限没有一个人
How? No one has access. No one.
你为什么不把它关掉？
Why didn't you shut it down?
你为什么不关闭海格力斯？
Why didn't you shut Heracles down?
我只对我的国家负责 而不是你
I answer to the interests of my country, not you.
- 对菲利克斯·莱特呢？- 我当然不会听菲利克斯·莱特的
- And to Felix Leiter? - I certainly don't answer to Felix Leiter.
也许是因为他已经死了
Perhaps because he's dead.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很尊重莱特
I had a lot of respect for Leiter.
如果你有什么消息 我很乐意知道
Look, if you have information, I'd be happy to receive it.
- 带我去贝尔马什 - 没有
- Get me into Belmarsh. - No.
布洛菲尔德是幽灵党唯一还活着的成员
Blofeld's the only member of Spectre still breathing.
- 我不能冒险 - 但你愿意冒险和一个腐败科学家一起研发DNA靶向武器十年？
- I can't risk that. - But you'll risk developing a DNA targeting weapon with a corrupt scientist for ten years?
没有证据表明奥布鲁切夫在为别人工作我抓住他了…
There was nothing to suggest that Obruchev was working for anyone else. I had him…
我的天 你现在渴了
My God, you're thirsty at the moment.
你没有权利那样对我说话
You have no right to speak to me that way.
你没有权利影射我的判断
You have no right to make insinuations about my judgment.
如果你没有什么可以给予 那你就无关紧要了
If you've nothing left to give, you are irrelevant.
你已经尽了你的努力 我们再次感谢你的服务再见
You've done your bit and we thank you for your service, again. Goodbye.
钱班霓 叫007进来
Moneypenny, send in 007.
你可以走了 邦德
You can go, Bond.
绝对是同一张桌子
It's definitely the same desk.
- 谢谢 - 嗯
- Thank you. - Mm-hmm.
去贝尔马什
Go to Belmarsh.
我要布洛菲尔德听到的 看到的 摸到的所有东西都扫描一下
I want everything that Blofeld listens to, looks at and touches scanned.
扫描牢房的每个角落
Scan every corner of that cell.
扫视整个监狱
Scan the whole prison.
事实上 把整个人都扫描一遍
In fact, scan the whole damn man.
先生 我会带上我的手套
Sir. I'll bring my gloves.
- 詹姆斯… - 嗯…
- James… - Uh…
你晚饭准备吃什么？
What are you doing for dinner?
- 所以你没死？- 你好 Q我很想你
- So, you're not dead? - Hello, Q. I've missed you.
- 嗯 - 闻起来真香
- Mm! - That smells great.
你在等人吗？
Were you expecting somebody?
嗯…不什么…原谅我
Um… No. What… Excuse me.
哦
Oh.
这是我第一次… 他20分钟后到 我无法转移注意力…
This is the first time I've… He'll be here in 20 minutes, I can't take my focus off…
我要你告诉我上面有什么
I need you to tell me what's on that.
不 我得把桌子摆好
No, I need to lay the table.
你知道 现在它们都是带毛的
You know, they come with fur these days.
我想说清楚 我无权帮助你
I want to be very clear that I am not authorized to help you.
- 我发誓… - 跟赫拉克勒斯有关
- And I have sworn… - It's to do with Heracles.
我猜M不知道发生了什么
I presume M doesn't know that this is happening.
没有 但肯定有事发生 Q
No, but there's something going on, Q.
我们得查出是什么
We need to find out what it is.
从来都不是朝九晚五 对吧？
Well, it's never 9:00 to 5:00, is it?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
- 嗯 邦德？- 是吗？
- Um, Bond? - Yes?
你知道这都发生在哪里吗？
Do you know where this has been?
我想 到处都是
Everywhere, I should imagine.
进入沙盒
Into the sandbox.
哦谢谢你！
Oh. Thank you.
这是一个数据库
Um, it's a database.
请不要碰那个
Don't touch that, please.
数据是什么？
What's the data?
- 它的DNA - 多个人
- It's DNA. - Multiple individuals.
M在做什么？
What was M working on?
他几年前就该关闭的东西
Something he should have shut down years ago.
- 哦 你好 - 什么？
- Oh, hello. - What?
- 还有更多 - 隐藏文件
- There's more. - Hidden files.
就在爆炸发生后 我被要求尽可能地从奥布鲁切夫的硬盘中恢复 我有一种很好的预感…
I was asked to recover what I'd from Obruchev's hard drive after explosion, and I've a pretty good feeling.
这就是我们所缺少的是的一个完整的磁盘
This is what was missing. Yeah. A complete disk.
这么说 奥布鲁切夫在为杀死幽灵党的人卖命？
So, Obruchev is working for someone who managed to kill all of Spectre?
不是所有的
Not all of them.
布罗菲尔德
Blofeld.
你能给我看看其他文件吗？
Can you show me the other files?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
等等 这不可能是幽灵党干的
Wait, this can't just be Spectre.
哦 我的上帝有数以千计
Oh, my God. There are thousands.
他们是谁？
Who are they?
他们在类别
They're in categories.
我需要更多的时间来整理…
I'm gonna need more time to organize…
世界上保存DNA信息的数据库都遭到了入侵
There have been, uh, breaches round the world of databases holding DNA information.
- 我们一直在追踪他们 - 我们的吗？
- We've been tracking them. - Ours?
不管他们是谁 都不能把我们排除在外
I can't imagine they're leaving us out, whoever they are.
布洛菲尔德会知道他们是谁的
Well, Blofeld will know who they are.
Q 你得带我去贝尔马什
Q, you need to get me into Belmarsh.
他只会跟一个人说话
Well, there's only one person he'll speak to.
谁？M说没人有权限
Who? M says no one has access.
- 真的吗？- 是吗？
- Really? - Did he?
那是什么？
What's that?
在世界爆炸之前 我能过一个美好的夜晚吗？
Can I just have one nice evening, please, before the world explodes?
谁有权访问？谁？
Who has access? Who?
- 早上 - 早上
- Morning. - Morning.
- 新病人 - 他很奇怪
- New patient. - He's weird.
你不能这么说
You can't say that.
对不起 我迟到了
I'm sorry I'm late.
我没想到会有新病人
I wasn't expecting a new patient.
抱歉让你吃惊了
Sorry if I surprised you.
不我喜欢惊喜
No. I like surprises.
作为一个心理治疗师 你很有魅力
You're very attractive for a psychotherapist.
对你的客户来说肯定很危险
Must be dangerous for your clients.
他们通常对自己更危险
They are usually more of a danger to themselves.
Foxgloves
Foxgloves.
美丽
Beautiful.
- 是你选的吗？- 是的
- Did you choose them? - Yes.
我发现他们很友好
I found them friendly.
你知道 如果你吃了它们 它们会导致你的心脏…
You know if you eat them they can cause your heart to just…
停
stop.
那我保证不会
Then I'll make sure not to.
你对花很了解吗？
Do you know a lot about flowers?
我父亲有一个花园
My father had a garden.
他教我
He taught me.
他在我年轻的时候就去世了 但我的兴趣还在
He died when I was young, but my interest remained.
失去父母是很痛苦的
It's difficult to lose a parent.
尤其是在年轻的时候
Especially at a young age.
是的 死亡对孩子有特别的影响 不是吗？
Yes, death has a particular effect on children, doesn't it?
它对你有什么影响？
What effect did it have on you?
深远的
Profound.
但我救过一个人的命
But I saved a life once.
我觉得这影响更大
I think that had more of an effect.
这是为什么呢？
Why is that?
救一个人的命会让你永远和他在一起 就像夺走他的命一样
Saving someone's life connects you to them forever, the same as taking it.
它们是属于你的
They belong to you.
我不太擅长谈论自己 所以我带了个记忆盒
I'm not very good at talking about myself, so I brought a memory box.
我想你们可能会感兴趣
I thought it might interest you.
有时物体比记忆更能唤起人们的回忆
Sometimes objects can be more evocative than memories.
我从没忘记你在冰下的眼睛
I never forgot your eyes under the ice.
他们需要我
They needed me.
这么多年后再见到他们真是令人震惊
It is a shock to see them so many years later.
他们仍然需要我
They still need me.
我被他们迷住了
I am rather taken by them.
- 你想要什么？- 帮个忙
- What do you want? - Just a favor.
你欠我
You owe me.
你杀了我母亲
You murdered my mother.
你父亲杀了我全家
And your father killed my entire family.
的父母
Parents.
我需要你帮我去见一个人 戴着这个
I need you to visit someone for me, wearing this.
它对你无害
It's harmless to you.
你是唯一能做这件事的人
You are the only one who can do it.
不
No.
我为什么要为你做事？
Why would I do anything for you?
因为我是一个愿意杀死你最爱的人的人
Because I am a man willing to kill the person you love most.
我已经失去了所有我爱过的人
I've already lost everyone I've ever loved.
你拿什么都威胁不了我
There is nothing you can threaten me with.
听你这么说我很难过 玛德琳
That is very sad to hear, Madeleine.
但这不是真的…
But it is not true…
不是吗？
is it?
玛德琳斯万，真的吗？
Madeleine Swann, really?
嗯 是的我们很重视你的信息 但那是五年前的事了没有什么了
Well, yes. We took your information seriously, but that was five years ago. Nothing came up.
她很聪明 也很擅长藏东西
Well, she's very smart and very good at hiding things.
她是个有用的人才
She's a useful asset.
她是他唯一愿意和他谈话的心理医生
She's the only psychiatrist he agreed to speak to.
我不得不行使我的判断力你的判断是问题所在
I had to exercise my judgment… Your judgment is the problem.
那件武器是用来拯救生命并消除我们特工的附带伤害的
That weapon was designed to save lives and to eradicate collateral damage for our agents.
每次都是干净准确的一击
A clean, accurate shot every time.
但必须是秘密的
But it had to be off the books.
我们的国家安全漏洞已经够多了
There are enough holes in our national security.
- 如果全世界都知道它的威力… - 他们会为之疯狂的
- If the world knows what this can do… - They'd kill for it.
听着…
Look…
如果是错误 责任在我 这是公平的
If it's an error, it's on my shoulders, fair and square.
我毕生致力于保卫这个国家
I've dedicated my life to defending this country.
我相信捍卫这些原则…这一点
I believe in defending the principles of this… Of this.
但我们过去可以和敌人共处一室 我们可以直视他的眼睛
But we used to be able to get into a room with the enemy, we could look him in the eye.
现在，…
And now the…
敌人只是漂浮在空中
The enemy is just floating in the ether.
我们都不知道他们在找什么
We don't even know what they're after.
布罗菲尔德
Blofeld.
我们设法进入了他们目标的数据库
We managed to access a database of their targets.
“我们”？
"We"?
哦 看在上帝的份上
Oh, for fuck's sake.
我明白了
I see.
布洛菲尔德死后 他们想要什么？
And after Blofeld, what do they want?
嗯 很难说
Well, it's hard to say.
我的意思是 我会想象世界领导人 无辜的平民 自由 你知道的 诸如此类的事情
I mean, I would imagine world leaders, innocent civilians, freedom, you know, that sort of thing.
很好 还是老样子
Oh, good, well, just the usual.
还是老样子
Just the usual.
布洛菲尔德通过一个仿生眼和他在古巴的特工联系我们现在已经取回了
Blofeld was communicating with his agents in Cuba through a bionic eye which we've now retrieved.
不客气
You're welcome.
幽灵党的毁灭会带来巨大的后果
Spectre's destruction's going to have huge consequences.
不管是谁干的他都是非常危险和强大的
Whoever did this is going to be very dangerous and very powerful.
我们需要我们能收集到的所有信息
We need all the information that we can gather.
先生
Sir.
邦德
Bond.
所以谣言是真的你看起来很好
So the rumors are true. You look well.
坦纳
Tanner.
长官 有新的进展
Sir, there's been a development.
它们就这么一个接一个地掉下来了
They were just dropping, one right after the other.
至少可以说 这是令人不安的
It was disturbing, to say the least.
等着看它近距离的样子吧
Wait till you see what it looks like up close.
- 邦德在办公室 - 什么？
- Uh, Bond's in the office. - What?
- 哦 邦德 天啊 我好久没见你了 - 退休后过得怎么样？- 闭嘴 Q
- Oh, Bond. My God, I haven't seen you in, in, uh… - How is your retirement? - Shut up, Q.
我知道他和你在一起
I know he's staying with you.
你也不是清白的
And you're not in the clear either.
- 发生了什么事？- 他被恢复了双0的身份
- What happened? - He's been reinstated as a double 0.
- 00什么？- 你有什么发现？
- Double 0 what? - What have you got?
Q研究了我从葬礼受害者身上采集的血液样本
Q has studied the blood samples I gathered from the victims of the funeral.
看看这个
Just look at this.
我们在看什么？
What are we looking at?
这是一个死去的古巴幽灵党特工的葬礼
This is the funeral of one of the dead Spectre agents from Cuba.
这是他们与尸体有身体接触的家庭成员
And here are the members of their family who made physical contact with the corpse.
我们在他们所有人的血样里都发现了赫拉克勒斯
We found Heracles in the blood samples of all of them.
做得不错 诺米
Now, that's some good work, Nomi.
谢谢 长官 双0什么？
Thank you, sir. Double 0 what?
- 它们是什么？- …纳米机器人
- What are they? - They're… They're nanobots.
正确的
Right.
微小的生物机器人只要与你的皮肤稍有接触就能进入你的系统
Microscopic bio-robots that can enter your system by the slightest contact with your skin.
用DNA编程来针对特定的个体
Programmed with DNA to target specific individuals.
赫拉克勒斯是…它被设计成我们军火库中最有效的武器
Heracles was… It was designed to be the most efficient weapon in our arsenal.
在到达预定的目标之前 它无害地穿过人群
Passing through people harmlessly before reaching its intended target.
但奥布鲁切夫改造了纳米机器人这样它们就能杀死与目标有关的任何人
But Obruchev modified the nanobots so that they can kill anyone related to the target.
- 谁？- 既然是基于DNA的 经过了进一步的修改 是的
- Anyone? - Well, since it's DNA-based, with further modifications, yes.
家庭 某些遗传特征
Families, certain genetic traits.
单核苷酸变异和多态可以针对从个体到整个种族的范围
Single-nucleotide variants and polymorphisms that could target a range from individuals to… whole ethnicities.
你感染了足够多的人 这些人就成了武器
You infect enough people… And the people become the weapon.
它从未打算成为大规模杀伤性武器
It was never intended to be a weapon of mass destruction.
这是…
It was…
我得给首相打电话
I need to call the Prime Minister.
坦纳 把死者家属和葬礼隔离
Tanner, quarantine the families from the funeral.
- 是 长官 - Q 黑进布洛菲尔德的仿生眼 看看有什么发现
- Yes, sir. - And, Q, hack into Blofeld's bionic eye, see what you can find.
你的愿望实现了
You've got your wish.
去找布洛菲尔德 看看能问出什么
Go to Blofeld and see what you can get out of him.
找到那只蟑螂 奥布鲁切夫
And find that cockroach Obruchev.
先生
Sir.
我们没有线索
We don't have a trail.
洛根·阿什 国务院前国务院
Logan Ash. State Department. Ex-State Department.
找到他 就能找到奥布鲁切夫
Find him, you'll find Obruchev.
嗯…祝你好运
Um… Good luck.
谢谢
Thanks.
等你做完重要的准备工作 我就在外面
I'll be outside when you're done with your important preparation.
我马上就来
I'll be just a moment.
它很好
It's fine.
布罗菲尔德的眼球解锁
Blofeld's eyeball unlocked.
访问接收的媒体流
Accessing received media stream.
我知道你和她有过一段历史 但这些年我们一直在密切关注她
I know you and she have a history, but we've kept a close eye on her over the years.
她很听话
She's been very compliant.
如果邦德在里面做了什么奇怪的事 你就帮了我一个大忙
If Bond does anything weird in there, you'll be doing me a huge favor.
所以别让他太轻松了 好吗？
So don't make it too easy for him, okay?
好吧
Okay.
他是这个国家最有价值的资产
He's the most valuable asset this country has.
我知道你和他有过一段感情 但别让他影响了你
I know you and he have a history, but don't let him get in your head.
如果你觉得自己失去了控制…哦 坦纳，放松
If you feel yourself losing control… Oh, Tanner, relax.
我不会…
I'm not gonna lose…
失控
control.
斯旺医生 下午好
Dr. Swann, good afternoon.
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
007.
- 六十七 - 二号特别牢房已关闭
- Six-seven. - Special cell two now locked off.
隔离装置安全
Segregation unit secure.
我们就到这里了祝你好运
This is where we leave you. Good luck.
给我们一个名字
Just get us a name.
能这么常和老朋友见面一定很开心吧
Must be nice to catch up with an old friend so regularly.
我们比以往任何时候都要亲近
We're closer than ever.
哦 太尴尬了
Oh, that was awkward.
他对所有女人都有这种影响吗？
Does he have that effect on all women?
五千零五十年
Fifty-fifty.
- 这是不可预测的 - 嗯
- It's unpredictable. - Huh.
在许孤立
Isolated in HSU.
你颤抖
You're shaking.
这不是一个理想的情况
It's not an ideal situation.
开门
Open the door.
打开这扇门！
Open the door!
- 不 - 什么事？
- Don't. - What is it?
詹姆斯 你不知道这是什么
James, you don't know what this is.
别逼我这么做
Don't make me do this.
请
Please.
对 把门打开
Right. Open the doors.
- 开门 - 开门
- Open the door. - Open it.
什么…
What…
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
回家
Home.
- 我去叫她 - 等待
- I'll get her. - Wait.
- 没有她他不会说的 - 只是等待
- He won't talk without her. - Just wait.
快递
Special delivery.
詹姆斯
James.
你好 布鲁弗
Hello, Blofeld.
也许你能帮助我
Perhaps you can help me.
古巴是个很棒的国家
Cuba was quite the party.
- 对了 生日快乐 - 谢谢
- Happy birthday, by the way. - Thank you.
我在想到底发生了什么
I'm trying to piece together what happened.
我是说 你在那里 或者在这里 和世界上最有权势的人 你的朋友们…
I mean, there you were, or here you were, with the world's most powerful people, your friends…
都在一个房间里 绞索套在我的脖子上 而你手上握着世上最珍贵的武器
All in one room, a noose around my neck, and your hands on the most valuable weapon in existence.
就像一个…就像是你伟大的见证
It's like a… It was like a testimony to your greatness.
这就是恩斯特·斯塔夫罗·布洛菲尔德
A celebration of all that is Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
是的 詹姆斯
Yeah, James.
是的
Yeah.
但后来一切都变了 不是吗？
But then it all went wrong, didn't it?
我亲爱的詹姆斯 你想要什么？
My sweet James, what do you want?
你的敌人正在逼近 布洛菲尔德
Your enemies are closing in, Blofeld.
最大的转折是如果你告诉我他们是谁 我就能救你的命
And the biggest twist here is that if you tell me who they are, I could save your life.
我的复仇天使
Mm, my avenging angel.
我那注定失败的追求者
My chaser of lost causes.
现在你还追我
Now you even chase mine.
但你问错问题了
But you're asking the wrong question.
没错 古巴是个令人失望的地方 但我们都会在生日那天哭
Yeah, Cuba was a disappointment, but we all cry on our birthday.
你得问问自己 我们为什么在这里？
You need to ask yourself, why are we here?
访问媒体文件
Accessing media file 472.
嗯 锋利 邦德
Hmm. Looking sharp, Bond.
473.
474.
475.
476、477、478
476, 477, 478.
479.
洛根·阿什 很高兴认识你
Logan Ash. A pleasure to meet you.
天啊 是他
Oh, my God, that's him.
对你的损失我深表遗憾
I am sorry for your loss.
我想你知道我代表谁 为谁工作吧？
I believe you know who I represent and work for?
我们给你一个机会
We have an opportunity for you.
你总是回到我身边
You keep coming back to me.
我以为再也见不到你了 但命运把我们拉到了一起
I thought I'd never see you again, but fate draws us back together.
是的Q看到洛根·阿什了
Yes. Q's got eyes on Logan Ash.
- 走吧 - 是的
- Go. - Yep.
告诉我发生了什么事
Let me know what happens.
现在你的敌人就是我的敌人
Now your enemy is my enemy.
这是怎么发生的？
How did that happen?
你活得够久了…是的看看我们
Well, you live long enough… Yeah. Look at us.
两个老家伙躲在洞里想搞清楚是谁在耍我们
Two old men in a hole trying to work out who's playing tricks on us.
她还爱着你你知道吗？
She still loves you. Did you know that?
你伤了她的心她背叛了你
And you broke her heart. And she betrayed you.
她是无关紧要的
She is irrelevant.
我可不会这么快就放弃
Mm, I wouldn't be so quick to dismiss.
你自己也说过 她很擅长隐瞒
You said it yourself, she's very good at hiding things.
当她的秘密被发现的时候 肯定会的 你会死的
And when her secret finds its way out, and it will, it'll be the death of you.
给我一个名字
Just give me a name.
玛德琳
Madeleine.
求你了… 求你了 别耍花招
Please, just… Please, no games.
玛德琳
Madeleine.
你知道吗？你们两个应该来见我
Oh, do you know what? The two of you should come see me.
夫妻心理治疗
A little couples therapy.
我只是想看看她告诉你真相时你的表情
I simply have to see your face when she tells you the truth.
告诉我他们是谁 布洛菲尔德…
Just tell me who they are, Blofeld…
然后我就走我会让你一个人呆着
and then I'll leave. I'll leave you on your own.
不 我不想让你走
No, I don't want you to leave.
我们只是在重新认识
We're just getting reacquainted.
嗯好吧来了
Hmm. All right. Come.
你非常有耐心我得给你点东西这样你就不会白跑一趟了
You were unusually patient. I need to give you sth. so that you didn't have to make all this way for nothing.
小心 邦德
Careful, Bond.
是我
It was me.
- 你摧毁了幽灵党？- 没有
- You destroyed Spectre? - No.
维斯帕的坟墓
Vesper's grave.
玛德琳什么都没做都是我的错
Madeleine didn't do a thing. It was all me.
我知道你会来的 我只是需要等待美好的时刻
I knew you'd come visit it, I just needed to wait for the bon moment.
她出于好心 直接带你去了
She led you straight there from the goodness of her heart.
然后你为了我离开了她
And then you left her, for me.
- 没关系 - 哦 但确实如此
- It doesn't matter. - Oh, but it does.
她现在还喜欢 不是吗？
She still does, doesn't she?
我可怜的小杜鹃
My poor little cuckoo.
你总是非常非常敏感
You were always so very, very sensitive.
这不管用
This isn't working.
继续
Keep going.
所有这些浪费的时间 你本可以拥有的生活
All this wasted time, the life you could have had.
这一切之所以如此美丽 如此精致的美丽 是因为你来找我寻求答案
The reason all of this is so beautiful so exquisitely beautiful is that you're coming to me looking for answers.
而唯一知道这一切的人 就是她
Whereas the one person who knows it all is she.
这是玛德琳她掌握着你需要的秘密
It's Madeleine. She holds the secrets you need.
他们所有人我没必要杀你
All of them. I didn't need to kill you.
我已经让你崩溃了
I'd already broken you.
我想给你一个空虚的世界 就像你给我的一样
I wanted to give you an empty world… like the one you gave me.
都快让我后悔了
It's enough to almost make me regret it.
嗯 差不多
Eh, almost.
死
Die.
嗯？
Hmm?
死，布罗菲尔德死
Die, Blofeld. Die.
耶稣开门
Jesus. Open the door.
邦德！邦德！邦德！
Bond! Bond! Bond!
开门 邦德！
Open the door. Bond!
杜鹃
Cuckoo.
你到底在想什么？
What the hell are you thinking?
对 对 我知道怎么审问线人
Yes, yes, yes, I know how to interrogate an asset.
- 审问结束了 - 坦纳 别教训我
- This interrogation is over. - Tanner, don't lecture me!
邦德 你违反了最重要的规则
Bond, you have violated the most important rule in the whole bloody playbook.
不要动
Don't move.
恐怕我需要这些
I'm… I'm gonna need those, I'm afraid.
他死了
He's dead.
幸好你们没有血缘关系 否则你也会死的
It's a good thing you're not actually related, or you'd be dead too.
- 我怎么把这个拿下来？- 你不知道你不能
- How do I get this off? - Oh, you don't. You can't.
纳米机器人不仅仅是为了圣诞节
Nanobots aren't just for Christmas.
海格立斯一旦进入你的身体 它就永远在那里了
Once Heracles is in your system, it's there forever.
他们找到车了吗？
Did they find the car?
我们追踪了 但她放弃了
We traced it, but she abandoned it.
他们搜查了她的公寓 她一直不在家
They searched her flat, she hasn't been home.
- 她是他们中的一员吗？- 我不知道
- Is she one of them? - I don't know.
詹姆斯 你知道她可能去哪了吗？
James, do you have any idea where she might have gone?
不我根本不认识她
No. I don't know her at all.
是给我的吗？
Is that for me?
不
No.
那你为什么还要来？
Then why did you come?
因为是你让我这么做的
Because you told me to.
我以为你不记得了
I didn't think you would remember.
我记得一切
I remember everything.
你得告诉我是谁给你下的毒 玛德琳
You need to tell me who gave you the poison, Madeleine.
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
是的 他已经死了
Yes, he's dead.
好
Good.
他告诉我你没有背叛我
He told me you didn't betray me.
我知道你天生就不善于信任别人
I understand you're not built to trust people.
- 你也不是 - 那我们就太蠢了
- Neither are you. - Then we were fools for trying.
我想
I wanted to.
我不知道你是不是想让我来这里 或者你为什么要杀布洛菲尔德
I don't know if you wanted me to come here, or why you tried to kill Blofeld…
或者是谁给你下的毒药 或者你为他们工作了多久 但我知道…
Or who gave you the poison to do it, or how long you've been working for them, but I do know…
在我生命的五分钟里 我想和你拥有一切
that for what felt like five minutes of my life I wanted everything with you.
不是因为我不信任你
And it's not because I didn't trust.
就是那种感觉
It was just that feeling.
我知道我来这是为了找出是谁给你下的毒
I know I've come here to find out who gave you the poison.
但如果你不知道我爱过你 我是不会离开这里的
But I'm not going to leave here without you knowing that I have loved you.
我也会爱你 我从不后悔我一生中遇到你的任何一刻
And I will love you, and I do not regret a single moment of my life that led me to you.
除了我把你送上火车的时候
Except when I put you on that train.
你知道你最糟糕的是什么吗？
Do you know the worst thing about you?
我的时间吗？
My timing?
不
Don't.
我的幽默感？
My sense of humor?
不
Don't.
- 什么？- 你看起来令人难以置信的
- What? - You look… You look incredible.
这是玛蒂尔德
This is Mathilde.
嗯…你好我是詹姆斯
Um… Hello. I'm James.
长官 我们找到洛根·阿什了 007想和你谈谈
Sir, we've located Logan Ash. 007 wants a word.
- 干得好 007 - 谢谢你 先生
- Well done, 007. - Thank you, sir.
准许捕获或杀死
Permission for a capture or kill.
我们跟美国人说清楚了吗？
Have we cleared this with the Americans?
理所当然谢谢你的关心
Granted. And thank you for asking.
遵纪守法 先生
By the book, sir.
你的前任可不那么恭顺
Well, your predecessor was less deferential.
说句公道话 邦德指挥官让我带路的
To be fair, Commander Bond gave me the lead.
我很高兴看到你俩相处得这么好
Well, I'm glad to see you two getting along.
先生
Sir.
找到斯旺医生了吗？
Have you located Dr. Swann?
恐怕没有 先生
Nothing, I'm afraid, sir.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
如果你听到什么 你会怎么做？
If you hear anything what do you do?
我躲起来
I hide.
很好
Very good.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
- 说晚安 - 晚安
- Say good night. - Good night.
晚安 各位
Good night.
她不是你的
She's not yours.
但是，嗯 …好吧 蓝眼睛 还有…她不是你的
But, um, the… Okay, the blue eyes, the… She's not yours.
好吧
Okay.
我有东西要给你看
I have something to show you.
另一个孩子吗？
Another child?
你爸爸和密室是怎么回事？
What is it with your dad and secret rooms?
跟我说话
Talk to me.
我本来想带你来的
I wanted to bring you here before.
告诉你一切
To tell you everything.
布洛菲尔德命令我父亲暗杀这家人
Blofeld ordered my father to assassinate this family.
这个男孩活了下来
The boy survived.
他的名字叫吕瑟弗·萨芬
His name is Lyutsifer Safin.
当我还是个小女孩的时候 他来这里杀我父亲
When I was a little girl, he came here to kill my father.
但他找到了我和我母亲
But he found me and my mother instead.
他饶了我的命
He spared my life.
现在他回来了
And now he's back.
- 他想要什么？- 复仇
- And what does he want? - Revenge.
我
Me.
- 他们是谁？- 幽灵党的投毒犯
- Who were they? - Spectre's poisoners.
我父亲为他们举行了宴会 用他们自己的食谱做了甜点
My father held a banquet for them, used their own recipe in the dessert.
二恶英
Dioxin.
他们会遭受极大的痛苦
They would have suffered horribly.
给他留下了终身的创伤
Scarred him for life.
这家人有一座岛屿
The family had an island.
他们称之为毒药花园
They called it the Poison Garden.
哦 所以布洛菲德从他们那里拿走了 并且继续经营它 现在这个萨芬又把它拿回来了
Oh, so… Blofeld took it from them, and kept running it, and now this Safin has taken it back.
Q 去找一个叫吕茨弗·萨芬的
Q, find one Lyutsifer Safin.
下落不明 也没有最近的照片 但我会给你发一些他小时候的照片
Whereabouts unknown and no recent photographs, but I'm gonna send you some images of him as a boy.
还有一张小岛的照片所以 你知道 尽你最大的努力
And a picture of an island. So, you know, do your best.
我需要一架飞机去那里 一架大飞机
And I'm gonna need a plane to get there, a big one.
我马上把我的位置发给你
I'll send you my location shortly.
你要去找他？
You're going to find him?
我们有一千个理由要找到这个人
There are a thousand reasons why we need to find this man.
你给了我杀他的理由
You just gave me a reason to kill him.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
怎么样？
How is it?
不错
Not bad.
原谅我
Excuse me.
- 什么事？- 邦德
- Yes? - Bond.
你找到那个岛了吗？
Did you find the island?
是的 这是日本和俄罗斯争议水域的一部分
Yes, it's part of a chain in disputed waters between Japan and Russia.
有一座化工厂可以追溯到第二次世界大战 似乎有很长的历史
There's a chemical plant dating back to the Second World War, seems to have had quite a history.
长官 日本情报部门报告岛上有可疑活动
Sir, Japanese intelligence have reported suspicious activity on the island.
Q 调出我刚发过去的卫星图像
Q, bring up the satellite images I just sent through.
这些是最近几天拍的
These were taken over the last few days.
- 如果那是萨芬… - 那么赫拉克勒斯也在那里
- If that is Safin there… - Then Heracles is there too.
你要这架飞机去哪里 邦德？
Where do you need this plane, Bond?
等等 Q 007找到洛根·阿什了吗？
Hang on, Q. Did 007 manage to locate Logan Ash?
她正在接近他我会把她的位置发给你
She's closing in on him. I'll send you her location.
我以为她在跟踪洛根·阿什 不是我
I thought she was following Logan Ash, not me.
什么？她是
What? She is.
詹姆斯 你在哪里？
James, where are you?
把她放在后面
Put her in the back.
- 你来了 - 在这里小心你的头
- There you are. - In here. Watch your head.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
我们要去冒险 亲爱的坚持下去
We're going on an adventure, darling. Hang on.
Q 我需要那架飞机 快
Q, I am gonna need that plane, quickly.
我在奥兰北约基地附近
I'm near Orland NATO base.
你觉得你能给我吗？
You think you can get it to me?
- 正确的对，是的 - 我们会去的
- Right. Right, yes. - We'll be there.
- 谢谢 - 妈妈
- Thank you. - Mama.
一只蚊子咬了我
A mosquito bite me.
没关系
It's okay.
豆豆 你喜欢蚊子吗？
Dou Dou, do you like mosquitoes?
妈妈
Mama.
- 蚊子有朋友吗？- 我不知道
- Do mosquitoes have friends? - I don't know.
我不这么想
I don't think so.
坚持下去
Hang on.
詹姆斯
James.
玛蒂尔德！
Mathilde!
他们已经超越了我们！
They're above us!
滚出去！詹姆斯！
Get out of here! James!
你呆在这里
You stay here.
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
任何人从那扇门进来 你就开枪
Anybody comes through that door, you shoot them.
除非是我
Unless it's me.
你安静点 好吗？保持很安静
You be quiet, okay? Stay really quiet.
嘿！
Hey!
走吧！走吧！
Go! Go!
那儿！撞死他！
There! Run him over!
漂亮的动作 邦德
Nice moves, Bond.
你阻止不了他…
You won't be able to stop him…
所以为什么不帮我呢 兄弟？
…so why don't you help me out, brother?
我有一个哥哥
I had a brother.
他的名字叫菲利克斯·莱特
His name was Felix Leiter.
需要搭车吗？
Need a ride?
你去哪儿了？
Where have you been?
追逐你的线索
Chasing after your lead.
- 阿什？- 死了
- Ash? - Dead.
他们带走了斯旺医生
They took Dr. Swann.
和她的女儿
And her daughter.
我不知道她有个女儿
I… I didn't know she had a daughter.
M拿到我的飞机了吗？
Did M get my plane?
我们的飞机我跟你一起去
Our plane. I'm coming with you.
谢谢你，007年
Thank you, 007.
- 你好Q - 邦德
- Hello, Q. - Bond.
抱歉把你从床上弄起来
Sorry to get you out of bed.
这项任务的目标有三个方面
The objectives of this mission are threefold.
确认赫拉克勒斯的存在
Confirm the presence of Heracles.
杀死奥布鲁切夫和萨芬
Kill Obruchev and Safin.
把斯旺医生和她女儿带离这个岛
Get Dr. Swann and her daughter off the island.
邦德 我希望他们在那里
And, Bond, I hope they're there.
- 谢谢你 先生 - 先生
- Thank you, sir. - Sir.
允许邦德指挥官被重新任命为007
Permission for Commander Bond to be redesignated as 007.
它只是一个数字
It's just a number.
很好同意了
Very well. Agreed.
祝你好运
Good luck.
键，你的手表
Bond, your watch.
它包含一个有限半径的电磁脉冲
It contains a limited-radius electromagnetic pulse.
- 它会使硬连线网络中的任何电路短路 - 如果你足够接近的话 - 嗯
- It'll short any circuit in a hardwired network - If you get close enough. - Mm-hmm.
它有多强？
And how strong is it?
这是相当强劲
It's fairly strong.
“相当强壮”是什么意思？
"Fairly strong, " what's that mean?
我们还没机会好好测试一下 小心点
We haven't had the chance to test it properly, just be careful.
对 这是Q-DAR
Right, this is Q-DAR.
当你穿过它时 它会映射出空间
It will map the space as you move through it.
不要碰
Don't touch that.
智能血液会追踪你…哎呦和你的生命体征
And smart blood will track you… Whoops. And your vitals.
邦德 你不介意工作的时候喝一两杯吧？
Bond, you don't mind a shot or two whilst at work?
- 好吗？- 我已经三四个小时没喝酒了… - 小时 - 哇
- Shall we? - Well, I haven't had a drink for three or four hou… - Hours. - Wow.
听起来不像你
Doesn't sound like you.
- 噢！- 好
- Ow! - Good.
我想你知道隐形鸟是怎么工作的吧
I assume you know how the stealthy bird works.
不，不知道
No, no idea.
重力
Gravity.
欢迎回来 萨芬先生
Welcome back, Mr. Safin.
欢迎来到你们家
Welcome to your family.
进展如何？
How are you progressing?
太好了 萨芬先生所以，很好
So, so good, Mr. Safin. So, so good.
- 我的请求吗？- 斯维特拉娜？
- My request? - Svetlana?
继续下去
Continue.
- 那是什么？- 保险
- What is that? - Insurance.
一根简单的头发从你头上掉下来 现在你的命就在我手里了
A simple hair falls from your head and now I have your life in my hands.
和你的
And yours.
威胁一个小女孩 你有多坏啊
How damaged you must be to threaten a little girl.
你受的伤少了吗？
You're any less damaged?
你爱上了一个杀手
You love a killer.
尽管他拒绝你 你还是生了他的孩子
You bore his child despite his rejection.
你这辈子都在隐瞒和撒谎
You've hidden and lied your whole life.
为了生存 你会做任何事
You will do anything… To survive.
你了解我就像我了解你一样
You understand me the same way I understand you.
移动
Move.
我父亲的花园
My father's garden.
这是他的有毒宝藏
It was his toxic treasure.
让我给她看看
Let me show her.
- 把她给我 - 没有
- Give her to me. - No.
我能保护她
I can protect her.
玛蒂尔德
Mathilde.
- 记住我跟你说的 - 别碰任何东西好吧？
- Remember what I told you. - Don't touch anything. Okay?
玛蒂尔德
Mathilde.
这是一个有毒的花园…但绝对安全
It's a poison garden… but it's perfectly safe.
这是我父亲做的
My father made this.
他非常爱他的植物 他会给它们唱歌
He loved his plants so much, he would sing to them.
我想给你看我最喜欢的一张
I want to show you one of my favorites.
其中一些植物非常危险 但并不是所有的植物都是用来伤害人类的
Some of these plants are very dangerous, but not all of them are for hurting people.
我有能做各种事情的植物
I have plants that can do all sorts of things.
玛蒂尔德！
Mathilde!
不
No.
这一招会让你乖乖听话 这样你就永远乖
This one makes you do as you're told, so you never misbehave, and you're always good.
你不能胡闹 玛蒂尔德
You mustn't misbehave, Mathilde.
你母亲也不能
And neither must your mother.
永远
Ever.
- 你喜欢这里吗？- 没有
- Do you like it here? - No.
好吧 你会学会的
Well, you will learn to.
我在这里长大 你也会
I grew up here, and you will too.
多么漂亮的孩子
Such a beautiful child.
也许我们应该喝点茶
Perhaps we should have some tea.
- 没有 - 让她看到光明
- No. - Make her see the light.
不 你不能把我们分开！
No, you can't separate us!
- 马蒂尔德！- 妈妈！
- Mathilde! - Mama!
- 记住我跟你说的 - 我去找你好吧？
- Remember what I told you. - I'll come looking for you. Okay?
别担心
Don't worry.
你有我
You have me.
一旦你在岛上有了视线 降低高度 保持在雷达以下
As soon as you have a line of sight on the island, drop altitude, stay below radar.
你以前开过这种飞机吗？
You ever flown one of these things before?
不
Nope.
别忘了打开降落伞 打开机翼
Don't forget to release the chute, and open the wings.
重力并不总是你的朋友
Gravity isn't always your friend.
在岛的西侧找一个混凝土结构
Look for a concrete structure on the west side of the island.
那是你进去的最好办法
That's your best bet for getting in.
来看看空气 Q
Coming up for air, Q.
正确的，很好
Right, good.
你应该进入二战时期的潜艇笔
You should be entering a World War II-era sub pen.
看起来不怎么活跃 但还是要小心摄像头
Doesn't seem to get much activity, but look out for cameras anyway.
用你的手表 邦德
Use your watch, Bond.
- 怎么回事？- 是设备的问题
- What's going on? - It's the equipment.
摄像头坏了
The cameras are down.
整个下界
The whole lower sector.
我重新启动系统
I'll restart the system.
好吧啊 这就对了
Okay. Ah, there you go.
- 长官 他们进来了 - 是的 我们有
- Sir, they're in. - Yes, we have it.
你应该能看到化工厂的结构
You should be able to see the chemical plant's architecture.
- 哪个是邦德？- 他就是PSI
- Which one's Bond? - He's the… He's the PSI.
- 他就是那个三叉戟 - 把布局给我们
- He's the trident thingy. - Give us the layout.
正确的
Right.
你在一个有毒的旋转木马的边缘
You're at the edge of a toxic merry-go-round.
主要活动应该朝向中央枢纽 它就在你的正上方
The main activity should be towards the central hub, which is directly above you.
邦德
Bond.
邦德 前面有个大东西 我不知道是什么是…这些墙一定很厚
Bond, There's something big up ahead, I can't work out what it is. It's… These walls must be thick.
邦德
Bond.
邦德？007 能听到吗？
Bond? 007, do you read me?
我们已经失去了他们
We've lost them.
他们进入了盲点 长官
They've entered a blind spot, sir.
我不知道他们走进了什么地方
I can't work out what it is they've walked into.
那就把它们拿回来
Well, just get them back.
你能看看那些门吗
Well, will you look at those doors.
这是一个导弹发射井
This was a missile silo.
正确的
Right.
我们走吧
Let's go.
- 大家到那边去！- 在角落里！现在！
- Everybody, over there! - In the corner! Now!
- 什么？如何？- 快走！
- What? How? - Move!
快！趴在地上！
Move! On the ground!
警报
Alarm.
下来，男孩
Down, boy.
你在干什么？
What… What are you doing?
你不能炸实验室 拜托
You cannot explode laboratory, please.
这是自杀式任务来吧
This is suicide mission. Come on.
你不能活着离开这个岛
You will never leave this island alive.
那是农场
That was the farm.
这是工厂
And this is the factory.
他们是大规模生产
They're mass-producing it.
诺米 过来看看这个
Nomi, come and look at this.
听着 你阻止不了的 先生
Well, look, you cannot stop it, mister.
我们有个大计划
We have big plan, you know.
- 我们有很多人 - 什么事？
- We have big numbers. - What is it?
这是一个模拟
It's a simulation.
它们不只是攻击个体
They're not just attacking individuals.
他们会杀死数百万人
They're going to kill millions.
这次箱子装不下了 女士
It will not fit in a suitcase this time, lady.
他真让我心烦
He's really getting on my nerves.
让他闭嘴
Well, shut him up.
噢！
Ow!
我的鼻子
My nose.
我们必须摧毁整个设施
We have to destroy this whole facility.
没有必要使用暴力
There is no need for violence.
萨芬先生 他们用炸药
Mr. Safin, they use explosives.
- 闭嘴 - 邦德先生 你有我的东西 我也有你的东西
- Shut up. - Mr. Bond, you have something of mine and I have something of yours.
你为什么不上来 我们可以谈谈？
Why don't you come up and we can talk about it?
像成年人
Like adults.
萨芬 他在哪里？
Safin, where is he?
如果我不回来 把这一切都毁了
If I don't come back, blow it all to shit.
我们没有足够的炸药
We don't have enough explosives for that.
是的 但他们不知道
Yeah, but they don't know that.
嗯
Huh.
他说你必须喝酒
He said you must drink.
- 为了你的健康 - 你信任他吗？
- For your health. - Do you trust him?
他让我杀了你上一个主人
He made me kill your last master.
不然他为什么会让你加入呢？
Why do you think he let you join him?
我觉得他想让你喝酒
I think he wants you to drink.
我想让他把我女儿还给我
I want him to give me my daughter back.
他说如果你规矩点 你就会见到她饮料
He said if you behave, you'll see her. Drink.
你知道这花是干什么的吗？
Do you know what this flower does?
它使你失明
It makes you blind.
只要在你眼睛里滴一滴 你就再也看不见了
Just a drop of this in your eye, and you'll never see again.
失去一只眼睛是一个悲剧
Losing one eye is a tragedy.
- 失去两个… - 别玩游戏 - 这不是游戏
- Losing two… - No games. - This is not a game.
欢迎
Welcome.
在地板上
On the floor.
你的火箭筒
Your sidearm.
小心
Careful.
- 她像羽毛一样轻盈 - 好吧！
- She is light as a feather. - All right!
请坐
Please, sit.
一切都会好的
It's going to be all right.
向你保证 一切都会好起来的
Promise you, it's going to be all right.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
暴力的历史
History of violence.
许可杀死
License to kill.
恩斯特·布洛菲尔德的仇杀
Vendetta with Ernst Blofeld.
爱上了玛德琳·斯旺
In love with Madeleine Swann.
我可以对着自己的倒影说话
I could be speaking to my own reflection.
我们的选择略有不同
We've made slightly different choices.
不我们只是为同一个目标开发了不同的方法
No. We've just developed different methods for the same goal.
只有你的技能会随着你的身体而消失
Only your skills die with your body.
我的在我死后还能活很久
Mine will survive long after I'm gone.
生活就是要留下一些东西
And life is all about leaving something behind.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
不需要很丑
Doesn't have to be ugly.
你离开我的孩子 我就离开你的
You leave my baby alone, I leave yours.
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
我想你是对的
I think you're right.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我想我们是一样的
I think we are the same.
我们都知道还没开战就失去了一切是什么感觉
We both know what it feels like to have everything taken from us before we're even in the fight.
要是有机会就好了 你不觉得吗？
It would have been nice to have a chance, you know, don't you think?
只是我们都应该有个机会
Just… we all should get a chance.
但你正在建造的这个东西 把所有人 整个世界都置于战场上
But this thing that you're building, it puts everyone, the whole world on a battlefield.
没人有机会
Nobody gets a chance.
没有人愿意承认的一件事是 大多数人希望事情发生在他们身上
The thing that no one wants to admit is that most people want things to happen to them.
我们对彼此撒谎说要为自由意志和独立而战 但我们真的不想那样
We tell each other lies about the fight for free will and independence, but we don't really want that.
我们希望别人告诉我们如何生活 然后在我们不注意的时候死去
We want to be told how to live, and then die when we are not looking.
人们想要被遗忘 而我们中的一些人天生就是为他们建造遗忘的
People want oblivion, and a few of us are born to build it for them.
所以 我在这里 他们看不见的神…
So, here I am, their invisible god…
在他们的皮肤下
sneaking under their skin.
你知道历史对扮演上帝的人是不仁慈的
You know that history isn't kind to those who play God.
你不知道吗？
And you don't?
我们都要消灭人类 让世界变得更美好
We both eradicate people to make the world a better place.
我只是想更整洁一点
I just want to be a little… tidier.
没有抵押品
Without collateral.
我想让世界发展 而你却想让它保持不变
I want the world to evolve, yet you want it to stay the same.
让我们面对现实吧…
Let's face it…
- 我让你多余了 - 没有
- I've made you redundant. - No.
只要世界上还有你这样的人就行
Not as long as there are people like you in the world.
恕我直言 你们取得了巨大的成就
And with all due respect to the enormity of your… tidy achievements.
但你们实际上只是站在一群愤怒的小人中间
All you're really doing is standing in a very long line of angry little men.
我没有生气 只是有点激动
I'm not angry, just passionate.
拆除你的炸药 离开我的岛 你就能带着这个珍贵的小天使一起走
Disable your explosives, get off my island, and you can take this precious little angel with you.
玛德琳？
And Madeleine?
- 她停留 - 你知道我不能这么做
- She stays. - You know I can't do that.
这是一种耻辱
That is a shame.
她真的希望你能
She really hoped you would.
她知道这是她生存的唯一途径
She knows it's her only path to survive.
不 你让她告诉我
No, you have her tell me that.
哪个母亲不愿为自己的孩子牺牲自己？
What mother wouldn't sacrifice herself for her own child?
你的也是这样吗？
Is that what happened to yours?
母亲躺在我的脚下 我看着她死去
My mother lay at my feet as I watched her die.
等等！
Wait! Wait. Wait.
我会照你说的做
I'll do whatever you want.
是的 你会的
Yes, you will.
我道歉
I… I apologize.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
选择很简单 邦德先生
Simple choices, Mr. Bond.
你想死在你女儿面前吗？
Like do you want to die in front of your daughter?
还是你想让你女儿死在你面前？
Or do you want your daughter to die in front of you?
不不不不不
No. No. No. No. No.
我很抱歉
I am sorry.
I'm sorry.
看看你父亲 玛蒂尔德
Look at your father, Mathilde.
这就是力量
This is power.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真的真的很抱歉
I'm truly, truly sorry.
詹姆斯！
James!
她在哪里呢？
Where is she?
- 第一批货在码头上 准备好了 医生 - 非常好
- The first shipment is on the dock, ready for pickup, Doctor. - Very good.
我的豆豆
My Dou Dou.
嗯…
Hmm…
如果你不想要我的保护 那就走吧
If you don't want my protection, then… off you go.
移动我们的第一批买家来了
Move. Our first buyers are arriving.
长官 我刚刚发现了一些可疑活动
Sir, I've just detected some suspicious activity.
几艘高速运输船正驶往该岛
Several high-speed transports are headed towards the island.
来源不明
Origin unknown.
还是没有007的踪迹
Still no sign of 007.
来吧 邦德你到底在哪里？
Come on, Bond. Where the hell are you?
这是没有希望的情况 女士请
This is hopeless situation, lady. Please.
邦德
Bond.
聚会人数超过了预定人数
The party is larger than the reservation.
听着 女士 求你了 放我走吧
Look, lady, please, please just let me go.
我…永远不会有出路的
I… There was never gonna be a way out.
停止这种废话
Stop this nonsense.
反正你也没机会了
You don't have a chance, anyways.
嘿我有一瓶好酒给你的人 给西非侨民这可能是件好事
Hey. Hey, I have a good vial for your people, good for West African diaspora. It can be a good thing.
我不需要实验室就能把你们整个种族从地球上消灭掉
You know, I do not need laboratory to exterminate your entire race from the face of the Earth.
- 你知道现在几点吗？- 什么？
- Do you know what time it is? - What?
死的时候了
Time to die.
不！
No!
动！动！
Move! Move!
他们下降到较低的一层
They dropped down to a lower level.
下面肯定有楼梯井
There has to be a stairwell down.
妈妈？
Mama?
我的小豆豆不见了
I lost my little Dou Dou.
玛蒂尔德玛蒂尔德
Mathilde. Mathilde.
我到处找你你在哪里？
I looked for you all over. Where were you?
我照你说的藏起来了
I hid like you told me.
我爱你
I love you.
我也是我爱你
Me too. I love you.
我们应该去
We should go.
我是Q 能听到吗？
It's Q. Do you read me?
请进 007 我是Q
Come in, 007, it's Q.
交通堵塞 我们有交通堵塞
Traffic. We have traffic.
- 我想我们是喝醉了 - 那是两架俄罗斯米格战机
- I think we just got buzzed. - Those are two Russian MiGs.
交通TCAS 你来控制
Traffic. TCAS, you have control.
我理解 我也在尽我所能
I understand, and I'm doing the best that I can.
请稍等
Just please wait.
长官 海军 日本 俄罗斯 都在盯着我
Sir, I've got the Navy, the Japanese, the Russians, all breathing down my neck.
想知道为什么我们让一架C-17在有争议的岛屿上空盘旋
Demanding to know why we've got a C-17 circling a disputed island.
先别告诉他们任何事
Don't tell them anything just yet.
- 啊 来得正是时候 - 诺米 你知道…玛德琳 玛蒂尔德 他们是我的… - 嗨 - 嗨
- Ah, just in time. - Nomi, you know… Madeleine, Mathilde, they're my, uh… - Hey. - Hi.
家人？
Family?
Q… 你在吗？
Q… are you there?
是的 邦德
Yes. Bond.
- 附近有皇家海军舰艇吗？- 哦 是的为什么？
- Do we have any Royal Naval vessels in the immediate vicinity? - Uh, yes. Why?
我们需要立即对这个地方进行打击
We are gonna need an immediate strike on this location.
整个岛 都是海格力斯的制造厂
This whole island, it's a manufacturing plant for Heracles.
我们没有导弹袭击的许可 对吧？
We don't have clearance for missile strikes, do we?
邦德 还有件事你得知道
Bond, there's something else you should know.
有几艘身份不明的飞船正朝你们驶来
Several unidentified ships are headed your way.
他们来找赫拉克勒斯了多远？
They're coming after Heracles. How far out?
嗯 20分钟
Uh, 20 minutes.
Q 给我接过去
Q, patch me through.
- 007 - M
- 007. - M.
我们的业务吸引了许多国际关注
Our operation is attracting a lot of international attention.
我们正在看我们能做什么
We're seeing what we can do.
来吧
Come on.
我们走吧来吧
Let's go. Come on.
外面会很冷的 所以我想把这个给你
It's going to get very cold out there, so… I want you to have this.
那会让你暖和的
That'll keep you warm.
我得把这个做完为了我们
I have to finish this. For us.
我知道
I know.
我马上就来
I'll just be a minute.
我有他们
I've got them.
这可能会派上用场
This might come in handy.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
Q 跟我说话
Q, talk to me.
我们的不速之客还有15分钟就到了
Um, our uninvited guests are 15 minutes away.
邦德 M 局势在外交上很复杂
Bond, M here. The situation is diplomatically complex.
我们别无选择听我口令开火
We don't have a choice. Fire on my mark.
如果我们发射 俄国人 日本人甚至美国人都会想知道答案
If we launch, the Russians, the Japanese and even the Americans will want answers.
那就别给他们
Well, don't give them any.
理性的头脑 邦德
Rational minds, Bond.
我在努力避免这场战争升级为全面战争
I'm trying to save this from escalating to all-out war.
马洛里 如果我们不这么做 就没救了
Mallory, if we don't do this, there will be nothing left to save.
听我口令开火
Fire on my mark.
007 还有一个问题
007, there's another problem.
- 你刚进的那个房间 - 是的 我知道 我知道
- That room you were just in. - Yes, I know, I know.
我得打开防爆门
I've got to open the blast doors.
否则我们的导弹会像弹床一样被弹开
Otherwise our missiles will bounce off it like they've hit a trampoline.
是的 我知道 我知道
Yes, I know, I know.
- 找到控制室 - 应该在防爆门上方的塔里
- Find the control room. - It should be in a tower just above the blast doors.
导弹发射后大约需要9分钟
The missiles will take about nine minutes from launch.
你认为你能在船到达之前完成吗？
Do you think you can do it before the ships arrive?
有的是时间 有的是时间
Plenty of time, plenty of time.
- 邦德 - 邦德 听到了吗？
- Bond. - Bond, do you read me?
是的
Yeah.
是的 问
Yeah, Q.
我读你
I read you.
听起来你像是在打橄榄球
Sounds like you're in a rugby scrum.
我刚给别人看了你的手表
I just showed someone your watch.
真的让他们大吃一惊
Really blew their mind.
正确的，很好你找到控制室了吗？
Right, good. Now, did you find the control room?
我的俄语有点生疏 但我想是的
Well, my Russian is a little rusty, but I think so, yeah.
好的，问
Okay, Q.
我做了些调查
Uh, I've done some research.
- 旧图纸… - Q 我需要一些…是吗？
- Old schematics… - Q, I am gonna need some… Yes?
邦德？
Bond?
- 喂？- 电源
- Hello? - Power.
电源？
Power?
是的 基础设施必须追溯到20世纪50年代
Right, the infrastructure must go back to the 1950s.
所以这将是一个过于复杂和复杂的交换系统
So it's going to be an overly complicated and intricate switching system.
现在 你进行的顺序需要非常精确
Now, the order in which you engage it will need to be extremely precise.
你要找的是控制面板
You're looking for a control panel.
应该有一个平衡离合器
There should be a counterweight clutch.
仔细听好了 007
So, listen very carefully, 007.
你要做的第一件事是…明白了
The first thing you need to do… Got it.
我想
I think.
是的 就是这样发射导弹
Yep, that's it. Launch the missiles.
除非你安全了
Not until you're clear.
Q 告诉M现在发射导弹
Q, tell M to launch the missiles now.
好吧好吧，好吧理解
Okay. Okay, okay. Understood.
M 邦德说开火
M, Bond says fire.
我是 HMS Dragon
HMS Dragon here.
- 上将 - 长官
- Admiral. - Sir.
- M在这里 - 我的指示是什么？
- M here. - What are my instructions?
你可以发射了
You have permission to launch.
收到开始攻击
Roger. Launching the strike.
- 导弹发射 - 九分钟后到达
- Missiles airborne. - Nine minutes out.
不
No.
不不，不！
No. No, no!
你搞得一团糟像一个动物
Quite a mess you've made. Like an animal.
现在我们都被心碎毒死了
Now we are both poisoned with heartbreak.
这是我们自己酿成的悲剧中的两位英雄
Two heroes in a tragedy of our own making.
我们碰过的人 就是他们的诅咒
Anyone we touch, we are their curse.
轻抚脸颊 亲吻…会立刻杀死他们
A stroke to their cheek, a kiss… would kill them instantly.
是的…玛德琳
Yes… Madeleine.
是的 马蒂尔德
Yes, Mathilde.
是你逼我这么做的 明白吗？
You made me do this, you see?
这是你的选择
This was your choice.
Q… 你在吗？
Q… are you there?
邦德 你来了
Bond, there you are.
他们安全吗 Q？
Are they safe, Q?
是的 他们是安全的
Yes, they're safe.
邦德 你离开这个岛了吗？
Bond, have you left the island?
防爆门有点小问题
There's a slight problem with the blast doors.
马上就好
Won't take a sec.
不，不，不邦德 导弹已经发射了
No, no, no. Bond, the missiles have already launched.
快离开那里
Just get out of there.
Q 我怎么 呃…我要怎么毁掉它？
Q, how do I, uh… How do I destroy this?
如果发射井的门是开着的 导弹就会对付它
If the silo doors are open, the missiles will deal with it.
不如果你把它带在身上 …你怎么把它弄下来？
No. No, no, no. If you get it on you, how do… How do you get it off?
你和我一样清楚 你不能
You know as well as I do that you can't.
它是永久性的
It's… It's permanent.
它是永恒的所以我们必须摧毁它
It's eternal. Which is why we have to destroy it.
看在上帝的份上 詹姆斯 快离开这个岛
For Christ's sake, James, just get off the island.
它是无害的 除非你离目标很近
It's harmless unless you're near to the target.
- 是的 - 那没用的
- Yeah. - Well, that's not gonna work.
哦 上帝哦 上帝
Oh, God. Oh, God.
这是玛德琳
It's for Madeleine.
没事的 Q
It's all right, Q.
没事了
It's all all right.
请让玛德琳接电话好吗？
Would you put Madeleine on, please?
是的 当然我真笨
Yes, of course. How stupid of me.
- 诺米 进来 - 你能让Madeleine接电话吗？
- Nomi, come in. - Can you put Madeleine on?
玛德琳
Madeleine.
- 詹姆斯 - 玛德琳
- James. - Madeleine.
我在这里
I'm here.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
这是做什么？
Is it done?
- 詹姆斯？- 是的
- James? - Yes.
是的 …他死了
Yes, he's… He's dead.
- 你们两个都在吗？- 是的
- Are you both there? - Yes.
好你是安全的这很好
Good. You're safe. That's good.
你离开了吗？
Have you left?
不嗯…我撑不下去了
No. Um… I'm not gonna make it.
什么？
What?
- 玛德琳玛德琳 - 你承诺
- Madeleine. Madeleine. - You promised.
快离开那个岛
Just get off that island.
我知道你能行
I know you can do this.
现在一切都很好
Everything's good now.
没人能伤害我们了
There's no one left to hurt us.
玛德琳…
Madeleine…
你创造了我见过的最美丽的东西
you have made… the most beautiful thing I have ever seen.
她是完美的
She's perfect.
因为她是你亲生的
Because she came from you.
哦 上帝瓶
Oh, God. The vial.
你被人投了毒
You've been poisoned.
是的
Yes.
一定有办法的
There must be a way.
我们只是需要更多的时间
We just need more time.
要是我们有更多的时间就好了
If we only had more time.
你有世界上所有的时间
You have all the time in the world.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
她的眼睛和你的一样
She does have your eyes.
我知道
I know.
我不知道该说什么 但我觉得我们应该聚在一起记住
Very hard to know what to say, but I thought we should gather and remember.
我觉得这样很合适
And I… I thought this was appropriate.
“人的功能是生活 而不是生存”
"The function of man is to live, not to exist.
我不会浪费我的时间去延长它们
I shall not waste my days trying to prolong them.
我要利用我的时间”
I shall use my time."
詹姆斯
To James.
- 詹姆斯 - 詹姆斯
- James. - James.
詹姆斯
James.
好了 回去工作
Right, back to work.
玛蒂尔德
Mathilde.
我要给你讲一个…
I'm going to tell you a story…
关于一个男人的故事
about a man.
他的名字叫邦德
His name was Bond.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
∮ 我们都有 ∮
∮ We have all. ∮
∮ 时间 ∮
∮ The time. ∮
∮ 在这个世界 ∮
∮ In the world. ∮
∮ 时间对生活来说足够了 ∮
∮ Time enough for life. ∮
∮ 展开 ∮
∮ To unfold. ∮
∮ 所有珍贵的东西 ∮
∮ All the precious things. ∮
∮ 爱在等待 ∮
∮ Love has in store. ∮
∮ 我们都有 ∮
∮ We have all. ∮
∮ 爱 ∮
∮ The love. ∮
∮ 在这个世界 ∮
∮ In the world. ∮
∮ 如果我们只有这些的话 ∮
∮ If that's all we have. ∮
∮ 你会找到 ∮
∮ You will find. ∮
∮ 我们不再需要什么 ∮
∮ We need nothing more. ∮
∮ 每一步 ∮
∮ Every step. ∮
∮ 路 ∮
∮ Of the way. ∮
∮ 会找到我们 ∮
∮ Will find us. ∮
∮ 带着关怀 ∮
∮ With the cares. ∮
∮ 世界的 ∮
∮ Of the world. ∮
∮ 在我们身后 ∮
∮ Far behind us. ∮
∮ 我们都有 ∮
∮ We have all. ∮
∮ 时间 ∮
∮ The time. ∮
∮ 在这个世界 ∮
∮ In the world. ∮
∮ 只是为了爱 ∮
∮ Just for love. ∮
∮ 没有别的了 ∮
∮ Nothing more. ∮
∮ ∮
∮ Nothing less. ∮
∮ 只有爱 ∮
∮ Only love. ∮
∮ 每一步 ∮
∮ Every step. ∮
∮ 路 ∮
∮ Of the way. ∮
∮ 会找到我们 ∮
∮ Will find us. ∮
∮ 带着关怀 ∮
∮ With the cares. ∮
∮ 世界的 ∮
∮ Of the world. ∮
∮ 在我们身后 是的 ∮
∮ Far behind us, yes. ∮
∮ 我们都有 ∮
∮ We have all. ∮
∮ 时间 ∮
∮ The time. ∮
∮ 在这个世界 ∮
∮ In the world. ∮
∮ 只是为了爱 ∮
∮ Just for love. ∮
∮ 没有别的了 ∮
∮ Nothing more. ∮
∮ Nothing less. ∮
∮ 只有爱 ∮
∮ Only love. ∮